This is Software Engineering Radio, the
podcast for professional developers on
the web at se-radio.net.
SE Radio is brought to you by the IEEE
Computer Society and by IEEE Software
Magazine online at
computer.org/software.
>> Hello everyone. [clears throat] Welcome
to today's episode of Software
Engineering Radio. Our guest is Sonali
Verde. Sonali is senior software
engineering manager at LinkedIn. She has
more than two decades of experience
leading engineering teams across
architecture, product dev, and platform
deliveries. Today, we're going to chat
with Sonali about how AI is changing the
engineering manager role. Sonali, before
we begin, I should note that I know you
through my network and have followed
your career for some time. I think
you're particularly well qualified for
this conversation given your experience
as well as LinkedIn's early adoption of
AI. That said, is there anything you'd
like to add to your bio before we start?
>> Hi Kanchan, happy to be here on this
podcast with you. The only other thing I
would add is that I also love to mentor
and coach early career managers and walk
them through some of my journeys and
lessons.
>> Okay, let's start with your own job. If
I followed you around for a week, where
would I actually see AI showing up in
your work?
>> All right. I think if you followed me
through the week, I think my first
meeting of the week starts with like an
operational review. We have a lot of
systems, legacy and new, that we own and
a lot of time goes in making sure that
we have like a right level of
operational rigor. And so, the first
early signs of where I needed to have
automation was actually having lot of my
operational dashboards automated in a
way that I could synthesize that
information for my leadership as well as
my VP level org. And so if you followed
me, you will see that every week there
is like what are the new signals, what
are the new insights, what are the new
experiments that the team launched or
did. And so a lot of time goes into
understanding some of those operational
nuances and that's where you would see
me using a lot of AI skills or trying to
automate things in a way that's easier
for my team to understand and digest
what signals we should be debugging
more. And two is like for me to uplevel
how do I communicate some of the things
that I am seeing in a way that can be
summarized and synthesized better for my
leadership.
>> Can you just talk about what
specifically changed here because of AI?
I'm assuming a lot of the automation was
in place. You talked about
summarization.
Perhaps that's an example, but what else
changed due to AI?
>> So you have lots of dashboards, right?
And so those dashboards do have multiple
systems that have different kinds of
dashboards and tooling. Right? If you
are on a legacy system, the legacy
system has like a different kind of
automation and a tool output that is
available for you. Then you are on newer
systems and newer systems have probably
been on boarded to like a newer tool and
things like that. And so there was a lot
of switching and making sure that we
were taking data from multiple tools,
multiple places and then trying to
create our own visual or like a
spreadsheet of how do we understand the
metrics that matter. So the first thing
that I was able to do is actually build
like a cloud skill, right? That can now
go through these different systems,
understands what exactly from that
output I'm looking for, and creating
this daily summary, if you will, for me
in a way that A, I don't have to run
like this 1-hour review meetings with
multiple managers coming and talking
about their systems. And so, it's
reduced the meeting time. It reduced a
lot of conversations about was there
data available or not. All of those
things happened in the background. And
when we came into the meeting, we were
actually able to focus on the real
insights that were the problem for that
particular operational review. And so,
it just up-leveled a little bit in terms
of where we used to start the
operational review to where we are now.
>> Thanks, Ali. That's helpful. For people
that may be not too familiar yet with
Claude skills, can you explain what that
is? And then, maybe get into a little
bit of a detail on how exactly you use
that here, and why that was not possible
before AI.
>> I would say that it's not that it wasn't
possible. It needed to have that level
of rigor of figuring out what the
current job should be. And there was a
little bit of the grind that was never
prioritized. And once we got access to
Claude, Claude actually had like an
easier way to onboard all of these
things in a way that you could speak to
it as like a natural language, right?
Like you can talk about it as if like,
"Hey, these are the things that I do.
Here are the links that I go to. And
here's what I actually look for as an
output." And it's almost like a chief of
staff kind of a skill. If there was
somebody who could help me with a task,
it's literally like Claude skill is
almost like you are telling someone the
actual task in a way that you would
explain it to another human. And then it
actually says, "Okay, here's how I
understand you. Here's what I think is
the output that you're looking for, and
here's what I can do." And then builds a
skill that you can then say, "Okay, run
this every day morning, or run this
before my ops meeting, and then send out
an email on the data that is missing to
my leaders, or whatever, right? It has a
way that once you have like the basic
skill, you are actually able to talk to
it and make it even better.
>> How does this compare with prompts that
were all the rage a year ago?
>> I think when we were thinking about
prompts, we were talking a little bit
more of using them for solving customer
kind of a problem. Like we were thinking
about prompts and AI of like, "Hey, how
can this help in solving something that
is more of like uh
economics or a business problem, right?"
We weren't as focused as what we would
do with it from like an internal
developer productivity or coding kind of
tasks. We were thinking about coding
kind of tasks, but they were a lot more
of as if a step up of like an IntelliJ
or an Eclipse automation. We were not
thinking about it from the power that it
could have of just automating like
end-to-end workflows. We were thinking
of them in a lot more compartmentalized
way is what I would say. Even with
IntelliJ or Eclipse, you had like an
automation of boilerplate code, and we
just thought, "Hey, with the prompts, we
could go one step further and have
something that's a little bit more built
out, right? Or template-based kind of
things." So, we were thinking a lot more
smaller, I would say, than how we are
thinking about it now.
>> Sounds like it's positive, but do you
have any example where
the AI told you, in this case you're
using Claude, so AI told you that
something looked useful and convincing,
but was actually wrong?
>> Yeah, it tells you what you should be
doing. At the same time, you still have
to use human judgment and look yourself
for some of the depth. I definitely, as
I was trying to adopt some of these
tools and see where and how I could
coach my team members to use it. I used
it in writing or bug fixing some of UX
bugs. And a lot of times, I do come from
a back-end engineering background, and
so there are things like accessibility,
there are things related to resizing,
reflows, kinds of architecture, where I
just took some of the inputs that the AI
agent gave me, and I implemented it only
to find out during the code review from
my tech leads that this is not the right
implementation. There was really no bug
in the regular flow. The bug actually
happened in a reflow kind of an
architecture of this UX. And so, I
actually learned that even though you
could use some of the AI tooling, you
have to still have human in the loop.
You need to understand the context. You
need to understand the depth. The skills
of like hard debugging, the skill of
actually having the context in which you
are looking at the problem is supremely
important, and that's my biggest
learning with using some of these agents
in my day-to-day. How I make decisions
about when should I trust it completely
versus when should I trust, but go with
a caution?
>> So, understanding is key, even though
you are getting the AI's help in
synthesizing and perhaps thinking to a
large extent.
>> Yes, absolutely.
>> So, you did give examples where you're
using Claude in this case to help you
work through what metrics should be
used, in this case also to do a bug fix,
which you felt was a good start, but
couldn't replace human judgment and
understanding. Are you also as a manager
using AI to actually, as an agent, to do
things beyond suggesting code changes,
for example?
>> So, the places where my team is actually
using is creating like agents for
automation of some of our workflows. One
of the examples that we recently had is
we do have like when some feature is
ready for bug bashing, we go through
like a bug bashing sheet, we come up
with which platforms are people testing,
and then we log all of these bugs in a
spreadsheet first, and then we import
that spreadsheet into our Jira
workflows. One of the things we did was
we just created a bug bash agent, right?
So, as the cross-functional team comes
together for an end-to-end bug bash,
they still use the same sheet for
logging of the bugs, but then how do we
triage those bugs? How do we then import
them into actual Jira? How do we
prioritize these things for like what's
really a blocker, non-blocker? So, some
of these tasks my team has started to
actually build agents that will help us
with this kind of efficiency. This helps
us a lot with multiple teams are having
multiple bug bashes, and so this has
reduced a lot of our manager and tech
lead times in some of the process
automation.
>> What is the difference between a and an
agent?
>> Yeah, skill is something that you can
share with people who have similar
problems. So, let's say if I look at
certain dashboards, most of the senior
EMs within the team have a similar kind
of an ask, right? To look at their own
systems and their own dashboards. And if
I write a skill, it's something that is
easily shareable. It's the same thing
with agent, but an agent is actually
performing a task on your behalf. Skill
is like you actually invoke it whenever
you want. Um it's just doing summary and
synthesizing and letting you know. You
could build skills that are actually
then become like composite skills could
become an agent, right? And so, skill's
a little bit more of an atomic unit for
your own kind of a task, if you will.
>> So, easier to get started with skills.
Over time, you can compose multiple
skills into agents.
>> Yes.
>> Do you also
get AI's help maybe to suggest the
skills based on what you do on a
day-to-day basis?
>> I actually have not used it to suggest
skills because the way I was looking
initially was I know a bunch of things
that I don't like doing, right? Like
it's just too much of a grind. I tried
to have like an Eisenhower metrics in my
head when I go in on a Monday, right?
What's urgent and important? What is
like non-urgent and important, but I
just don't have time to get to it,
right? And so, that's kind of how I went
into, "Okay, here's where I would love
to have skills so that they are all
important tasks, but I don't want them
to become like this urgent thing." I am
sure that now that I have used so much
of Claude that Claude knows a lot about
like how I think or how I do things. And
over time, I'm sure I could just ask it
for suggesting a skill, and it would
start recommending some of these. But, I
haven't yet started to use it in that
mode.
>> But, it certainly seems like AI has
changed the balance of time as a
manager. You do some things less, and
you do some things more. What is it that
you are able to do more now?
>> One particular thing that I definitely
feel like I can do more is I have like
lots of ideas about where my team should
be investing in, what should we be
working on. Sometimes it's product
ideas, sometimes it's platform ideas,
sometimes it's just ideas that are like
I love to just explore, right? And what
could be possible, what should we be
doing, and things like that. I feel now
I have lots [clears throat] of ideas
into like these mini prototypes, if you
will. And I feel like I don't have to
spend a whole amount of time preparing
presentations or decks, and like
convincing my cross-functional partners
or like my peers or my direct reports on
to something, because I'm actually able
to have a lot more solid prototype, if
you will, to get them on the same page.
>> Now that we have talked a little bit
about how your day-to-day has changed,
let's talk about the team. As AI has
become part of everyday engineering
work, what did you have to change first?
Did you have to make sure that there was
certain context in place, certain
frameworks in place, to make the team
effective with AI? Can we start with
that?
>> So, I will say that we started this AI
adoption around 9-10 months ago. It
started with should we use cursor or
WinSurf or GitHub Copilot to start
augmenting to the tasks that we were
doing. And we started to see with just
adoption, right? How many people were
actually adopting any of these AI tools
that were becoming available say last
August or September. And that's the only
thing in my mind or I guess even in our
leaders' mind is let's have people
starting to adopt these things and then
we will see if there is anything in
there. I think the true adoption started
happening with Claude Code coming out in
early January and a lot of us using
these tools during our hackathon week.
And that was actually a truly
transformational moment. I think
personally for myself as well as for a
bunch of people on my team. We used
pretty much all the AI tools that were
available out there. We used Replit for
some app mockups. We used Claude Code
for coding. We used Gemini for
presentations. And I think that's where
all of us started to feel a little bit
like there is something here that's
truly going to help us understand. And
then I think in February and then after
February I would say, our goal initially
was let's have adoption metric, right?
Let's have everybody use it. Including
us as managers. And once all of us
started using it, we started sharing our
learnings. There were some people who
were early adopters and those early
adopters actually showed us what all can
be done. Like I talked about the bug
bash agent or somebody else wrote some
other agent. And that's kind of how we
started sharing in our team share outs
or our company shareout and we actually
created an environment of learning
through these shareouts and plugins and
sharing skills and it became a little
bit more infectious I guess that oh
you're seeing something that's really
valuable to your team. Why don't I use
it in my team kind of a thing and that's
when more team members starting to use
it and now it's almost like everybody on
the team is using AI tools for the code
that they write or the tasks that they
do.
>> What do you see separating people that
use the tools well versus others? Like
what are the specific new skills that
matter more?
>> I think what matters is sometimes when
we have a lot of experience, I think our
first way of doing a task is very much
hard set in our minds because it feels
like oh I know how to do this myself,
right? And I'll take an example of my
own self like when I get called into an
on-call incident, I know what my steps
are. It's almost like a muscle memory
that's there. I know which dashboards to
go, I know which logs to check, I know
which regex to like actually look for
for a certain kind of an error or a
pattern and it's very easy for me to do
it myself than actually saying oh looks
like there is a new operational agent
that's out there. Let me talk to that
agent and let me try to explain to that
agent what I'm looking for in the logs
and I think for somebody who has a lot
more experience, it's harder because
your muscle memory, your things with
your code base, the things that you
know, it's easier almost to do it than
to like ask for how to do it. But it's
easier for people who have not
implemented something, who are new on
the on-call roster, if you will, for
them to be able to know these things.
And if they are alone without a tech
lead, let's say at midnight, they get a
phone call. For them, it's so much
easier to be actually saying, "Hey, I My
team owns this particular code base.
What are the kinds of errors that I
should be looking for? Or what are you
seeing as the errors that have exceeded
P99s or P95s or whatever, right? And so,
I feel like there is that little bit of
asymmetry of knowledge that's there. So,
it's again up to people for how they
want to use it and how they can use it
to up-level themselves. I have realized
that now some of the tasks that are
muscle memory for me, they are only
within my repos and what I own. But I
don't have that muscle memory for
something that's across the boundary or
across the org. And I actually feel like
the agent is really helping me cross
that boundary, right? Instead of calling
that other team's on-call engineer, I
can do some more debugging before I
decide, "Okay, let me page somebody
else." So, I feel like there is still a
lot of learning, I will say. But at the
same time, I feel like it's helping
cross boundaries a little bit better.
>> It's very interesting insight that you
really have to unlearn certain things
before you can use AI effectively.
>> Yeah.
>> This leads me to my next question. Let
me explain that a little bit. Just
taking your example of the on-call
and somebody that's new at this, they're
maybe firing off multiple threads with
the AI to understand what might be going
wrong.
Potentially multiple agents. So, is
there a perspective you have with
respect to the fact that the engineers
themselves now have to gain some
managerial capabilities in managing
multiple threads or multiple agents as
they do their day-to-day work. This is
something I've heard that software
engineers now are becoming managers of a
team of agents. Do you see any truth to
that in practice? From your experience?
>> I actually think that and maybe this is
like my whole brain is into this whole
system thinking, right? I think as
engineers we always had this
multitasking, multithreading kind of a
mindset. So, there is a chance as like
you are junior in your career, you don't
know where to start and you like have
three, four, five agents. Let's just
take an on-call that they just fire out
to see what will come back, right? But
I'm a big believer of learning by doing.
It's okay if somebody puts four, five
agents as long as they are in their
token count, I guess. I'm okay with
whatever they're doing. But I think you
learn over time, right? Like you learn
that okay, all these multithreaded
architectures, they could all like lead
to too many garbage collections or dumps
and things like that. And so, I think
what's going to happen or this is like
maybe my speculation a little bit here,
but I do think that it's going to help
us up-level ourselves faster, right? We
will actually onboard a little bit
faster. We will actually get to that
depth a little bit faster if we just are
not afraid of failing through having
multiple agents and learning. I think
the most important thing is are you
curious and are you learning? Are you
actually reading the output of these
agents? Are you understanding why like
two three agents conflicted with each
other and actually produce something
that wasn't the right outcome, right?
And as long as people are willing to
learn, I think it's okay to learn by
failing. I do think that people are
learning and adapting faster given the
fact that they are understanding that
okay, maybe this was a direction that
didn't lead an outcome. Right? So, okay,
this is not how I should think. The next
task they are like, okay, I just need
one or two things that I need agents
for. So, I think like that learning I'm
seeing happening within my team and I
think it's going to happen even in the
broader industry.
>> Maybe I can re-ask a question with a
potentially better example. Now that a
lot of the work is done by the AI
agents, the coding agent, for example,
or testing agent if somebody's created
it. Are the more effective engineers
able to take on more projects at the
same time because they're able to manage
these multiple trends or agents?
>> I think the answer is definitely yes.
From like a building perspective, they
are able to take on multiple tasks or
multiple projects. I think the places
where I still am yet to see the outcomes
is are all of these things in the right
direction and are we going to have like
3x more throughput and things like that?
I think that is still something depends
on how complex is your architecture, how
complex is some of the things that you
depend on other teams and how
distributed, how much of legacy, how
much of new build that you have. And so,
I think the answer is there is somewhere
in the middle, but you definitely see
that lot of engineers are able to take
on more building tasks and a lot of time
is spent on code reviews, deployments,
operational excellence, hard debugging,
testing of some of these projects. So,
like the time to build is shrinking. The
other parts are like you have to now
figure out how do you optimize the
deployment cycles, the test cycles, and
other things on the operation side.
>> Let's now spend some time in how you
talk to the team, how do you coach the
team, what are you hearing from the team
as everybody is using more of AI?
Perhaps, could you share an example of a
specific one-on-one where AI changed the
conversation in some way?
>> Yeah, I had a skip level one-on-one with
somebody who had just joined the team,
very young, early in career, and we were
just having a conversation of how these
new AI tools are helping. And one of the
questions very organically came up was,
"Hey, how do you get evaluated?" And I
talked about like, you know, the metrics
that I get evaluated on because this is
a new engineer, he wants to know how his
skip or whatever gets evaluated in their
performance reviews and stuff. Which I
thought was a very nice question to ask.
And I talked about the fact that from a
quality perspective, I get rated on
triage rate of our team. And this person
asked me, "What is that metric now?" And
I said, "Looks like our triage rate
across all the teams that report into me
seems to be 5 days." And he was like,
"Why is it 5 days?" And I'm like,
"Because we have this process and this
process and then like it goes through
like all of these steps." And this
person went back, looked at all the
flows, and actually built a triage agent
that reduced our triage time across all
the tickets that we had to 9 hours,
right? And just the realization that I
had was having just a conversation on
something that I get evaluated on and
what the published metric was, someone
was able to think about how can we make
that better, right? And it's not that we
didn't have triage tools before. We did
have triage tools. They were very
text-based triage tools. This person was
able to actually figure out how do we
add visualizer to this triage tool, what
kinds of other things that we could add
to make this much better. And so I feel
like some of these conversations and
one-on-ones have changed. It's also like
up-leveling and inspiring other people
on the team to think bigger. And the
things that they didn't think about were
possible before, everybody feels now
that things are possible or at least
making an attempt to make them possible.
>> So that's certainly a very positive
example. Have you had any negative
interaction on the use of AI? I mean,
there's certainly a lot of negative
emotions associated with that as well.
>> Yeah, of course there are negatives,
right? This is at the end we're actually
building software. There are a lot of
things like we also go through where we
have made mistakes as humans, right? I
have written code in production that
caused a production issue when I was a
junior engineer and have those things
definitely happen. One example that I
had was we tried to integrate an agent
within our on-call alerts. And I got
paged at 3:00 a.m. for this particular
alert and I tried to use the agent to
debug it and the results were so all
over the place that for almost an hour I
felt like I was misguided by its
investigation because of the
hallucinations that the agent had and
not understanding the system. And I
literally had to say, "Okay, I'm not
going to look at this output. I'm going
to use my first principles thinking and
I'm going to go through the stack one by
one to figure out where the problem is."
And I think my engineers are also facing
some of these things. There is
definitely a chance that there will be
things that are not good and you have to
constantly challenge things from a first
principles basis. Don't just take the
output of the agents and assume that
it's all like the greatest output. Use
your first principles thinking, your
systems thinking, especially if you're
working on critical systems, critical
problems. They have to have a certain
level of rigor and we cannot lose this
first principles system design way of
thinking about some of these outputs.
>> So, with that, with coding becoming
faster, with designs outputs becoming
potentially faster, and you mentioned
review is critical. Now, is review the
new bottleneck? Do you have to really
treat that as a very first class work
instead of something, I believe, you
know, we've thought of engineers do
reviews also.
>> Yeah, actually we'll talk about a funny
situation where I mentioned to one of my
senior most ICs how the joy of coding
has come back in like managers' life.
And this person says, "And the joy of
code reviews is taken away from my
life." And so, it was a very funny
banter, but you are spot-on. Reviews are
the big bottleneck right now. There is a
lot and lot of pressure on senior most
ICs to make sure that they are holding
that gate and the bar and the guardrail
and figuring out what level of
automation is needed so that reviews
don't become a bottleneck. Because the
expectation is that we will have
meaningful impact with lot more
experimentation, lot more throughput.
And so right now one of the biggest
challenges is figuring out the reviews,
the deployments, the testing cycles. How
do we do meaningful innovation on those
aspects of software development and test
life cycles so that we are shipping
scalable products.
>> So at this point in time, do you see
real evidence that the same team can do
more or has the work really shifted into
figuring out how to do better reviews
and provide oversight and validations?
>> I'll tell you the things that I feel
have become easier to build. I think
operations, like when you are building
like APIs, you have always have this
create, read, update, delete kinds of
CRUD APIs, right? Building those things
has become really easy. There are things
within the system design of something
like oh this needs an offline compute,
this needs some kind of a nearline
thing. This needs like a pub/sub
architecture. All of those parts of the
build that design thinking, that upfront
thinking about how do you want to think,
how do you want to break out certain
architectures, I do think that that it
has given us more time to think about
some of the things upfront and it has
helped with like reducing this CRUD kind
of work that we used to do. I think even
in the review side of things, I will say
that we do have like automation review
stuff which does a great job on like the
crud APIs and that those reviews, right?
The reviews where things are a little
bit complicated is just like the context
of the whole architecture and stuff. So,
I do see the build velocity has gone up.
I think the testing deployment
infrastructural side of things are the
ones where we're still not seeing as
much gain. It's helping with debugging,
I would say, right? Like when you're
doing some offline compute if like your
data jobs or whatever are failing,
definitely have AI helping us debug
something faster than we would have done
before, but that's an area where it's
not like it it understands our own data,
data lineage, data policies, and things
like that. And so, we definitely have
not seen gains in that area. But, crud
side of things, we definitely have seen
a lot of gain.
>> Are you measuring productivity? I've
heard of token usage discussed as a
metric. Is that useful or is that really
really measuring effort and activity?
What other metrics are you using?
>> We are going through a lot of different
ways of thinking about developer
productivity. I think for adoption and
usage, we definitely look at token.
Again, token usage tells you that
everyone who is adopting is figuring out
whether to use it in a plan mode,
whether to use it in an execution or an
agent mode. And so, it tells you a
little bit of the adoption, I will say.
The other parts of the metrics are how
often is your trunk getting blocked? You
know, how often are like PRs getting
reverted and things like that. So, all
of those metrics are something that I am
actually pushing the team to start
measuring, right? And not just have like
the token usage. Token usage kind of
tells you a little bit more horizontal
like adoption metric, if you will, but
not really a throughput metric. And so,
the throughput metric comes with the
number of experiments that the team is
able to do, the number of initiatives
the team is now able to ship, the number
of times that has reduced self-inflicted
incidents, if you will. So, those are
some of the metrics that I'm actually
pushing for, because that actually give
you a little bit more about the system
health.
>> Are you also measuring just how much of
the code is written by AI at this time?
>> We do have all the adoption metrics have
the lines AI produced lines of code,
token usage, like you said. All of those
things are definitely part of the
adoption metric of the team. The system
metrics and stuff
is also something that I'm keeping an
eye on, right? Which is making sure that
with this AI metrics going up, the
system metrics can't go down. Like they
have to stay complementing each other.
>> So, I've also heard about people saying
we are now shipping more story points.
In which category does of metrics for
you does this fall under?
>> It falls under the number of initiatives
the team is able to ship, right? When
you talk about the number of story
points, what were story points? Story
points was our like estimates, right? As
developers, we were always optimistic.
We would give
some estimates and say that oh, we will
be able to deliver 10 story points a
week, if you were a four people team or
something like that. And now, you know,
with AI tools, people get just come up
with another estimate, right? I feel
like that guestimate was also something
that we never really like understood it
very well, but I think right now I feel
it's a lot more concrete in terms of how
much kind of actually gets shipped and
rolled out 200% right? And that is
really the meaningful impact rather than
just looking at Kanban boards and
looking at like story points and
velocity and story points. I think those
were all measures for us to be able to
flag risks early on, but I feel the
number the OKRs that you take on as a
manager to whether it's product OKRs or
engineering OKRs and how many do you
ship and roll 200% production is like
the new way of measuring the throughput.
>> So while we're on the topic on the
craft, I would like to ask you about the
methodologies. You did talk about the
fact that you do have story points
measured today and Kanban for certain
use cases. Is
the methodology of Agile Scrum that we
have followed for the last several years
still relevant in the age of AI? What do
you see as of now? What do you think?
>> I think it's changing even with Agile,
right? Every team used it in their own
different ways, right? Some teams still
did like a lot more waterfall upfront
thinking and then only when it went into
the build cycle did they follow like
some Agile practices. In some cases, I
come from startups and I remember we did
everything from like Agile, right? Like
your product design, engineers,
everybody was thinking about story
points. We didn't even know what MVP was
going to look like. And so I feel like
all of these Agile practices that are
there before, they are still going to be
valid in terms of how teams curate them
for their own use cases or outcomes that
they want. I would say one thing that
will change is everybody will be a
builder now, right? So, before in your
Agile teams, you had PMs and designs who
were doing certain aspects of the tasks,
but they were not building with you
together, but now those boundaries are
gone. They could be building with you.
They could be writing like let's say
product policies and things within the
code themselves, and it's not like you
have to translate it in some ways, and
so I feel like now the story points are
even going to be a bigger set because
it's going to be augmented with all the
different job functions together than
some of the ways where only engineers
were part of that story point
calculations.
>> Interesting. So, does that you believe
change the composition of the team
itself?
>> I think it will change. It's not
changing yet, but if I look at what I am
seeing now, I do believe that, you know,
in a year or two, the boundaries of who
builds what is definitely going to be
changing. And so, the composition of the
Agile teams will change. The
compositions of how we build and ship
things will change, and how we actually
use things will also probably change.
>> So, perhaps that's a good segue into
hiring and onboarding. With AI, you're
looking for different things when you're
hiring.
>> I think in terms of our modules that we
use for hiring, the only one that we
have added is AI native module, which is
what somebody's ways of using an AI tool
while they are thinking of solving a
problem. So, that's the one change that
we have done. Again, the way to kind of
grade this module, we are learning and
calibrating amongst ourselves as we kind
of understand different people and
different people's ways of using that AI
tool, but that's one change that we have
started to take into consideration. I
think the other part is I do spend a lot
of time in my interviews, which are a
lot more communications-wise,
on somebody's curiosity and adaptability
and willingness to learn any new skill.
And it doesn't matter whether it's
related to coding, debugging, just being
a team player, right? I think like those
are some of the things that I have
started to ask a lot more questions on
than I would before. So, those are the
changes that I'm doing in hiring side of
things. In terms of onboarding, again,
we used to initially have this
onboarding tasks. Were very simple
tasks, right? Like, "Hey, after your dev
boot camp, just pick up like one or two
backlog bugs." But now those bugs have
become like smaller automation tasks,
right? So, in terms of how are we
onboarding, we are actually onboarding
by doing a lot more than what we used to
have onboarding tasks before.
>> Do you have expectations around new
hire? Do you set expectations around
what is acceptable AI use and how should
they consider security and even
ownership of the output?
>> In terms of onboarding, we still use the
same 30-60-90 day template of what is
expected out of your performance at the
end of 30 days, 60 days, 90 days in
terms of AI adoption. Again, like I
said, in the first 30 days, I'm not
looking at them to be like a power user,
but at end of 60 days, I'm looking at
them to be wide and using all of the AI
tools that the team is using, right? For
doing whatever task. At the end of 90
days, you definitely want them to take
ownership of the outcome that they are
producing, right? And so that's
something that I don't think that it has
changed because of AI. I think it's just
the fact that you want that the maybe
the complexity of the task has become a
little bit bigger of what they own, but
I think my expectation is that at the
end of 90 days, you should feel like
you're part of the team and you whatever
you build, you own it and it's something
that you will continue to take the
ownership for. When hiring
>> and you did talk about everybody on the
team becomes a builder. Will continue
look for specialist perhaps in you know,
in their different areas, perhaps
specialist in architecture, specialist
in platform support or UX.
>> I think I will. I think each of the job
function brings a different creativity
to the table and so it's very important
that you have a team that has those
creative thought process. Like I said, I
come from back end engineering and there
are very lot of times when I actually
don't see difference between square
corners and rounded corners, right? But
I have engineers on my team who have
that UX specialty who are able to
actually see these things and can
actually say here's what a world-class
UX looks like. And so I do think that
there is the specialist part of it is
still very, very important because our
human judgment, our human way of
evaluating what good looks like, what
fair looks like, what great looks like,
cannot be taken over by an agent, right?
And so, I think even when I'm looking at
architects, I mean, there are still so
many times where I get called into the
architecture reviews and I'm like blown
away by some paper that they will talk
about or they'll talk about, "Here's how
we should be scaling." Or, "Here's kind
of what the new GPU map looks like." And
so, I do think that there is that
specialty of architects and the
experience and things that comes with
experience that is important in a team
and in building a successful team. So, I
would say that, you know, all of those
specialties exist.
>> In my mind, that does match with your
earlier comment that while AI can help
you with a lot, you still have to have
that understanding and the specialized
experience does help you with
understanding is probably your point.
>> Yes, absolutely.
>> Let's start to wrap up now and my first
question as we trying to wind down would
be, you've talked about how AI has
changed your day-to-day, some of your
discussions with your team, the work
done on your team. What about your peers
and your manager? How has AI changed
that interaction?
>> I think one good thing is all of my
peers and managers, we all participated
in that hackathon and went for a manager
coding camp. And I think that actually
set like the level of like, "Hey, here's
kind of what we can do together." Or,
"Here's something that I can do now
more." Or, like the whole exchange of
thoughts and what we could do really,
really helped. I think I mentioned this
to somebody recently. What makes us
managers in technology is because we
were technical leads and technologists
before, right? And so right now, we need
to go and explore that part of the
technologist or the tech lead that we
used to be by actually using these
tools, by actually doing some of the
tasks that are on your team's plate, and
getting that level of understanding so
that you actually can have good
conversations with your leaders, you can
have good conversations with your peers,
you can actually figure out what is
possible and what is not possible. Are
we all having the same problems of like
code reviews or deployments or like
whatever else, right? Like we can share
and gain from each other. And so if
there is one call to action for any of
the engineering managers out there is
don't have this anxiety because of AI
about your job. Just learn by doing it.
You don't need to have the same
throughput as your topmost IC on the
team, but you should learn so that you
can walk in their shoes, you can have
empathy to their problems, and you are
the spokesperson for them.
>> Is there anything you'd like to share
about any postings you follow, any
people you follow, or any podcasts that
you follow? How do you keep up with
what's changing every day?
>> I actually
just listen to I think the Anthropic's
engineering blogs and stuff. I will be
honest, I don't listen to a lot of
podcasts, but I'm always looking at what
Anthropic is doing in terms of their
technical evolution and stuff. So that's
one thing that I definitely keep up with
to understand. I do attend like lot of I
don't learn by watching trainings, if
you will. I like to do like dabble
myself and like get stuck and figure
things out rather than somebody shows me
how to do it. I don't think I learn
through watching YouTube videos or just
taking a learning course or whatever. I
do a lot of like blogs and tech blogs
reading.
>> Anything we missed that you'd like to
cover? You had a very specific call out
to all managers is, you know, actually
try the tools that your team's using.
Anything else you'd like to talk about?
>> I think outside of that, I know that
there is a lot of anxiety, lot of fear
going on. I think one thing which is
truly comes from like my experience is
keep the human aspect up and running.
Like make sure that your human judgment
is going to be supremely important in
the products that you build. And so it's
important that you don't get carried
into this thing that you lose that human
judgment, human intuition. Ask a lot of
questions, build the muscle to examine
things deeply so that you are also
growing in your own understanding of how
you should be building, how should you
think about the business, how you should
think about adoption of the products and
platforms or scaling. But that's the
only other thing that I would say. Like
be human, be empathetic, use these
tools. Don't get carried away with this
anxiety and what you hear outside.
>> That's nice to hear, Sonali. Not said
enough, I think.
>> [laughter]
>> How can people follow your work or get
in touch?
>> Yeah, they can add me on LinkedIn.
LinkedIn is a platform that I use a lot
to connect to all professionals, so will
be very happy to connect with people who
want to get connected.
>> Thank you so much for coming on the show
and sharing where you are in the journey
and I know it's early but sounds like
there's a lot of learning that you have
shared here and good luck as well.
>> Thank you.
>> [music]
>> Thanks for listening to SE Radio, an
educational program brought to you by
IEEE Software Magazine. For more [music]
about the podcast, including other
episodes, visit our website at
SE-Radio.net.
To provide feedback, you can comment on
each episode on the website or reach us
on LinkedIn, Facebook, Twitter,
>> [music]
>> or through our Slack channel at
SE-Radio.slack.com.
You can also email us at
team@se-radio.net.
>> [music]
>> This and all other episodes of SE Radio
is licensed under Creative Commons
License 2.5.
>> [music]
>> Thanks for listening.